Guide to the North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Records TAM.683
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Publications
  - Publications Created by NACLA
    - NACLA Newsletter and NACLA's Latin America and Empire Report, 1966-1972 (Box 4)
    - NACLA's Latin America and Empire Report and NACLA Report on the Americas, 1973-1984 (Box 5)
    - NACLA Report on the Americas, 1967-1992 (Box 6)
    - The Debray Case, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Who Rules Columbia?, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mexico 1968: A Study of Domination and Repression (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Researching the Empire, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - N.A.C.L.A. Research Methodology Guide: Office Copies, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The Hanna Industrial Complex, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The University-Military-Police Complex: A Directory and Related Documents, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Great South Asian War, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Military and Police Operations in the Third World, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Tupamaros, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Seminal Warfare: The Role of Latin American Studies, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - NACLA Research Methodology Guide, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - NACLA Packet #1, 1970 July 16 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - NACLA Packet #2, 1970 August 4 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - NACLA Packet #3, 1970 September 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - NACLA Packet #4, 1970 October 23 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - NACLA Packet #5, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - NACLA Packet #6, 1970 November 6 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - NACLA Packet #7, 1970 November 26 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - NACLA Packet #8, 1970 December 23 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - NACLA Packet #9, 1971 January 18 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - NACLA Packet #10, 1971 February 12 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - NACLA Packet #1, 1971 December 8 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - NACLA Packet #2, 1972 February 5 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - NACLA Packet #3, 1972 March 8 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - NACLA Packet #4, 1972 April 5 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - NACLA Packet #5, 1972 April 26 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - NACLA Packet #6, 1972 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - NACLA Packet #7, 1972 July 3 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - NACLA Packet #8, 1972 August 10 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Yanqui Dollar: The Contribution of U.S. Private Investment to Underdevelopment in Latin America, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - A.I.D. Police Programs for Asia and Africa: 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - The U.S. Military Apparatus, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - New Chile, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - The Incredible Rocky, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Rius: The Chicanos, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - NACLA's Bibliography on Latin America, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Guatemala, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Argentina: In the Hour of the Furnaces, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Estrategias de los EE.UU. para Centroamerica, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Las maquiladoras en Mexico: Nueva lanza del imperialismo, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Political Thesis of the Puerto Rican Socialist Party: The Socialist Alternative, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - NACLA Nicaragua (Spanish edition), 1976 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Immigration: Facts and Fallacies, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Carter's Immigration Policy: Attack on Immigrant Labor, 1978? (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Nicaragua 1979: Year of Liberation (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Strategies of U.S. Imperialism in Latin America, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - El Salvador Labor Report: February-March 1987 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Working Against Us: The American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD) and the International Policy of the AFL-CIO, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - NACLA's 25th Anniversary Celebration Program, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Publications Collected by NACLA
    - Basta Ya! by Canchimalo, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Guide to the American Left, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Guide to the American Right, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - USLA Reporter, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Center for Cuban Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cuba Review (Cuba Resource Center), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Progressive Periodicals Directory: 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - HURIDOCS (Human Rights Information and Documentation System): Provisional List of Organizations, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - CIEPRODH (Centro de Investigación, Estudio y Promoción de los Derechos Humanos): Guatemala: Informe especial sobre casos de tortura, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Media Coverage
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains files collected by NACLA that the organization referred to as "NACLA in the News," mostly from the 1980s and 1990s. Materials include newspaper clippings, press releases, and copies of articles on media consultation, staff writings outside of the organization, and opinion pieces on NACLA activities, including both praise and criticism from the left and right. This series also includes George Black's 1984 op-ed from The New York Times and the various reactions to it, illustrating an ideological rift in NACLA concerning the Reagan administration's involvement in the 1984 Nicaraguan general election under the Sandinista Directorate.
  - Reagan on NACLA, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Heritage Foundation Report, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Staff Activities: NACLA in the News, 1975-1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Staff Activities: Letters of Reference, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Staff Activities: Articles, etc., 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The George Black Op-Ed, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Staff Activities: NACLA in the News, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Media Consultation, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - NACLA in the News, circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Staff Activities: Ruth Kaplan, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Staff Activities: NACLA in the News, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - NACLA in the News, circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - NACLA Publicity: Attacks from Left, 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - NACLA Publicity: Attacks from Right, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Staff Activities: Reprints, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Use of NACLA Materials, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - NACLA in the News, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Opinions on NACLA, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - NACLA Press Clippings, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Description of NACLA, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Citations: NACLA in the News, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - NACLA in the News: Organizations Listing NACLA, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - NACLA in the News, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - NACLA in the News, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - NACLA in the News, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 36)